Hello friends,
today we are going to discuss about term plan,
why should one take a term plan, when should one take it, who
should take it and why is it necessary to take it. So we will
talk about it in detail.
Subscribe to our channel
so that
you can get notifications for videos like this. So let's get
started.
[Music]
Now friends, let's talk about what a term plan is.
Friends, whenever we talk about
life insurance, you have to pay
some money, you get some money
along with it, you get some tax. So, it is
a kind of mixed plan, in which you are
also saving some money, some of
your goals are being planned, like brother,
after 15 years, after 20 years, I need some money,
or if you take some money, then you get some money.
But the term plan is a
complete insurance plan, in which you do
not get any savings plan or any other plan, it is a term plan,
you get full life insurance at very low rates, in it as long as
you are alive, you are
managing your things, you are managing your family,
all your children.
You are managing everything like education,
any liability in your elders, you are also looking after that,
you are running any EMI, any loan,
you are managing all that,
you manage your business as well, but if for some
reason some misfortune happens to you and
after your death, your family is left without any burden,
whatever your ongoing liabilities were,
they can also be
completed and your family does
not have to take out a loan to pay them, then
term insurance is very useful for those things,
friends, the specialty of term plan is that it is very cheap,
you get it at a low price,
you get a very large amount for a low price,
now friends, let's talk about
who can take a term plan and why
you should take this term plan,
now let's talk about parents,
parents can
take this for their family, for their children
because as long as you are there, you are
bearing all the expenses of your family,
but after your death, to ensure that they get financial
support, you can do this  You
can take a policy, merit couples can take it
for each other, if you
want to take a policy for your wife, then you have your wife
and if
something happens to you then at
least your wife can get some financial support, whatever amount you
take, or if you are a
working person then you can take it for your spouse, you
can take it for your husband, you can
take it for your parents, if you are a
professional then you can take it, if you are
doing business then you can take it or if you have parents then you can take it for your parents, for those
parents who are
dependent on you,
if you are tax oriented then you can save
some money because the premium you pay will also be saved,
and if you want to take
protection for your family then that will also be
your goal, that will also be completed, so you
can take it on tax side also,
if you have made some such investment
for your family, for
your children in your family  You should get so much money for so many years
or you have to collect so much money for your
children's marriage and
education in so many years, so after your death, at least
when they get that
money, the company will give it to your nominee and your
family, then with that money, at least
your ongoing goals will continue,
you will not face any problem in that,
your family will
not face any problem there, apart from this, if
you have taken some loan for us, then you can take it,
your EMI is running, your tax is
running, your other brother is running,
you can take that, so you should take this term
plan in your life, the
sooner you take it, the lower will be
your premium, your premium will be set for life time,
its premium never increases
and the more time you take, the more
its premium will increase according to your future.
Now friends, let's talk about how the term plan
is a term plan, it works when you die,
now
friends, it works only on death, like for
mother, it works only when she dies, it works only when she dies.  If it
is accidental or
death due to any disease or any other 90% set,
this is also a plan, this is a
term plan,
suicide is taxed, there is no tax in it, for 1 year when you
take this policy, then in the first year you do
not have to pay tax, from the second year onwards, that too becomes taxed
in it, so these are all the things,
if you die due to these things,
then in this the company pays to your nominee, whoever
you are, if
these are not yours normally, if they are your legal ones, then it pays
them, to your parents,
whoever you make as nominee, the company gives them that much
money, whatever they have paid,
friends, now let's talk about some basic features,
friends, whenever you want to take this policy,
you can take this policy whenever you are 18 years old, if you want to take any policy above 18 years, then you can take it, the
coverage term which you can take will be
minimum 5 years, apart from that you can take as much as you want in this policy, if
you have 25 years ahead then
you can take it for 30 years  You can take this for a minimum of
5 years, meaning your next plus 5 years,
after that, whether you live for 10 years, 20 years, 50
years, 100 years or till your death,
you can take it on the graveyard anytime. The
premium you will have to pay will be
decided by it. If you
take the policy and you feel that the
things mentioned in the policy are wrong
or you are not satisfied with some things,
then you can take a free look at it, you
can cancel it within 30 days and the
entire premium you have paid will be
returned to you.
You can take one policy with this policy. You and
your wife or you and your husband can
take the same policy for your family.
Both will be covered under the same policy. If
something happens to either of them, then the
company pays the same amount to the nominee of the other person. So,
you do not need to take separate policies. If
you wish, you can also take separate policies.
In the same policy, both the
people can pay tax here.
Now let's talk about the coverage, how much should the tax be? So
you can take up to 25x on
annual income. If your income is 10 lakh
rupees, then
you can take 25 times of it. Your 25
times means you can easily take tax of 2.5 crores. So
whatever is your annual
income,
but if we talk about the maximum, then
you can take 20 times and 25 times the tax of your annual income.
Whatever coverage you take, we will leave it aside. Let's
talk about premium payment,
you can make premium payment monthly,
quarterly, half yearly or yearly. There is
no boundation in this that you have to make annual payment. There is
no foundation of any kind in this. You can pay monthly,
quarterly, half yearly or take it, there will be no
problem in this. Let's
talk about tax saving, so whatever
money you pay, you can show it in your income item.
You would get such comments in it.  And whatever benefit your
family gets, whatever money you get normally
or there are some plans in
which you also get the premium returned, then the
money of the head is
tax free, the
government does not have to pay any kind of tax on it,
if you receive your normal plan then
they also will not have to pay any tax on it, whatever
you have taken for whole life, for example, you have taken it
till the age of 75 and you have
lived that much from 75, you have lived beyond that and
you have invested some additional premium
which is return of premium
and the company returns the money, then
that money is also tax free for you, whatever
premium you have paid, you get it in full
there, so
that is also tax free for you, let's talk about premium, so
friends, it has been told from Tom Insurance that
whatever you take in future will be
free as per your future,
if you are taking it at the age of 18 then it is possible that
your premium of ₹1 crore is only seven
thousand rupees, 8000 rupees,
if you  If you are 50 years old then it is possible that
your premium of this one crore will be ₹40000. Let's talk about
payouts, whatever payout you want
your family to get or your family to get,
you can choose that as per your choice whether
you want
lump sum money, say you have taken a
sum of one crore, then your
family should get it in full or you should keep getting it in the
form of some monthly income,
25000, 30 or 50 rupees every month, whatever you select, you should keep getting it and
your
family should keep getting it or you want that at the
time of your death, whatever
money you have, you should get some lump sum and keep getting some
monthly income, then that thing
is also an option available here, so whichever option you choose,
you can do it,
accordingly your family gets the money. Let's
talk about premium payment option, so
friends, many premium payment options are
available here, if you want, you
can pay it in single installment when 40 years next  If you are
taking a policy for 40 years, then there is a
single payment. If you pay that, then
you will get the payment in one go.
You will not have to pay anything for your entire lifetime. If there is any
mishap, then whatever money you are
entitled to will go to your family. Or
you can make regular payments. You
can pay monthly, quarterly, half-yearly, or for however
many years you are taking the policy. If you are
taking a 40-year policy,
then you will have to pay premium every year for 40 years.
Or you can also take it on a limited plan.
What will happen in a limited plan?
Suppose you have taken a policy for 40 years,
you have to pay some premium only for ₹5 to 10 years. Just
like here you have to pay a single premium,
similarly in a limited plan you have to
pay premium for five to 10 years and
after that, all the things that will be free
after paying limited, your policy will continue. If there is
no loss from me, then the money will go to your
family. So you
can also do this. Let's talk about the grace
period.
Suppose you have taken a policy, your policy should be for one year.  If
your policy
expires, you have 30 days' time.
Now you can pay the payment within 30 days, then
your policy will remain active.
Now let's talk about policy revival.
Friends, policy revival happens when, for example, the
30 days period of your policy is over,
after that your policy becomes
inactive. Now that policy is running
but it is of no use to you. If there is
no such period, then you will
not get any money from it normally. So if
you want to revive it
again, if you want to restart it, then
you have 5 years' time.
You can restart that policy within 5 years.
Whatever premium
you had to pay, that is the premium, apart from that the
company charges you some charges.
After paying those charges, you
restart the policy and
after restarting the policy, you have a
waiting period of 3 months in it. On every revival, be it
in 1 year, 5 years or 3
years, whenever you revive the policy,
you will get the benefit for the next 3 months.  You will not get any claim. If
you die even after withdrawing for 3 months, then
your family
normally gets that money. Let's talk about the
premium taken ahead, so friends, the more
you comment, the more the company will pay and that
premium will be fixed for your lifetime. The more you
advance the premium, the
more premium you will get. Now friends, let's talk about the
things that you have to keep in mind when you take a policy,
how can you get a good policy.
Friends, first of all you have to keep in mind the
claim settlement ratio of which company you are
taking the policy. If you are taking a term insurance policy of any company, then first of all
you have to pay attention to
which company has the best claim settlement ratio.
Number two,
every company gives critical, like
some companies give 34 critical,
some companies give you 64-65 critical, which are
addressed. The
higher the maximum critical, the
more benefit you will get. Call it
accidental death rider, so friends, if
you also add this rider there  So
then the
benefit that your family is going to get, the
problem and what you have adopted, suppose
you have taken a sum of Rs 1 crore,
if you add it, then if death occurs
due to an accident, then some
extra amount is given to your
family, at a very small amount, suppose it is a
short of Rs 1 crore, if death occurs due to an
accident, then due to extended death, there
is Rs 50 lakh, Rs 1 crore, the company has added an
extra Rs 1 crore to it, so this
accelerator has to be checked whenever you take the policy, so
how much time will you get in case of death of the accelerator, how much have you taken, Rs
1 crore along with that, plus
if it happens with an accident, then
how much will the company pay you in that, so you also have to keep this in
mind,
permanent disability order, friends, suppose you had an
accident but you died,
you got permanent disability, then
you can also add such a rule there
that in case of permanent disability, the
premium will be written off to the company
or the company will give you the
lump sum or some income.  So
these types of writers are also there,
you can add such writers there, there is
also a premium var writer, in this in case
of death or any misshaping,
any permanent disability, any
total disability, then
in such conditions the company waives your premium
and your policy will
continue but you will not have to pay the premium there,
so we can also see this rider,
return of premium
rider, so friends, there is also a return of premium
rider, so whatever money you are paying,
that money will be
returned to you by the company at the time of expiry of the policy, suppose
you took a policy for your 40 years,
you have to pay a premium of ₹10000 per year,
so you have paid ₹4 lakh there in 40 years,
then suppose nothing happens according to these, then
on adding this rider the company returns the entire money to you,
but whenever you apply this rider,
your premium increases a little,
so you have to keep this thing in mind, if
then we increase  If it is increasing then you have to
write only that much in the policy, it is not
increasing that much, you feel that by adding a little
you are getting the premium return of premium,
if nothing happens to you on the end of the policy you will get your money back, then you
can also avail that there,
apart from that there is an online term plan, so
friends, at
any time you get two types of policies,
online you will get it and offline you will get it, so the effort is to
go more towards online
because whenever you buy a policy online,
you will get it cheaper, offline
you will get it a little expensive because the agent gets
commission in it, so there the
policy becomes a little expensive, so
online you will get it cheaper and offline you will
get it expensive, now friends let's talk about the
premium, friends, whatever premium you
can pay, on what things
is it decided and how much can it be good,
friends, the biggest factor is your income, if your premium is
less, your premium will be less, if your
premium is more, your premium will be more, so
buy this policy as soon as possible, buy the policy at your minimum age,
number two drinking habit,
friends, if you drink, whenever you
buy a policy then this question will be asked to you  You will be asked whether
you drink or
smoke. If
you have any of these habits, then
your premium can increase a little there,
which can range from 10% to 25%, 30%, 50%. The company will increase
your premium accordingly.
Fourth, if
you have any disease
[music]
and you tell the company about it and the company will do
your medical test once,
check it, will do a checkup, after that the company will
decide how much to
increase your premium, whether to give you the policy or not, so all these
things will be set by the community,
if you have this habit or you have any
disease, then the company will increase your premium there,
but once the premium is
fixed, then it will remain fixed for life,
it will not increase or decrease, so let's talk about
what documents are required when you take the policy,
friends, first of all your documents, PAN
card, Aadhar card, these are mandatory, they will be required
when you do it, therefore all your documents will be required there,
but if you self upload and do business
then  Your income tax will be applicable for
three years, it is mandatory to pay it there,
many companies accept it in two years
but most of the companies pay for three
years or two years, so the writer
takes
a photo of you if you are doing it offline and the
company conducts a medical test of yours, the company from which
you are
taking insurance will conduct your medical test, it will
conduct the medical test at their expense
so that they can know if you have any diseases in your body,
for that they
conduct a medical test, that is retirement,
after all this you can take the policy,
you will need these documents if
you are taking the policy offline or
online, then you have to
upload them there, online you can upload it directly
from your computer, your laptop, your mobile,
so in offline case you
need hard copies of these but in online case
you can upload everything on the system itself, so for that
you have to
take the documents, these get uploaded directly from the system,
so friends, this was our today's video about term
insurance, this video for you
Tell me how you liked it. If there is some answer, if
you want to get any information then you can ask us.
We have put our number in the description, so if
you want to get any information from there then
you can contact us and
get the information. Apart from this,
subscribe to our channel because we
make videos of our friends,
you keep getting notifications about them. Like our videos. If
you feel that this
video of ours is helpful
then you can also share it with your friends in your group.
Thank you.